Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Mama...Mama...
They're beautiful, Mama.
Yes, and when you grow older, I wish for you to become a gentle person like these flowers.
Sure.
April 20th, 2193 A.D.
I'm sorry.
This world is too cruel.
I just can't...
Mama !
I'm sorry.
My mother was gentle and fragile.
If gentleness and humanity can
kill people, I'd rather abandon it...
The Comet Empire has reached
the Mars final defense line.
The number of enemy ships has
passed 20,000, and is still increasing.
BBB squadron executed a short warp into the Comet's interior, but we lost contact.
The Comet Empire is maintaining its speed.
It's not like they have infinite war potential.
If we use the wave motion fleet to reduce
their numbers, we have a chance for victory.
Any update on the Yamato ?
According to a report from the Yamanami fleet, which rescued some of the crew members...
...there's no additional information after the ship fell into the interior of the Comet.
I'm afraid...
Say what ?
A safety device.
If what it says is true, the Zemurians must have made
a safety device to permanently shut down the Gatlantians.
Answer me.
I brought you here to know that.
It's classified.
We can't tell outsiders...
Answer the question.
As the last Zemurian I demand the answer.
It sings the song of destruction.
It's a yoke, and the most significant key...
...for controlling the Gatlantians.
It's called Golem.
Golem...
The Zemurians built it long ago.
Once activated, it will bring
death to all artificial humans.
Zorder swiftly took it when the revolt began...
...but he couldn't destroy it.
As soon as Golem is damaged, it begins to sing...
...the song of destruction which will kill man-made cells...
...that echoes through the universe.
So Golem still exists ?
Where is it now ?
What's wrong, Analyzer ?
They figured it out.
Lost the link at a time like this ?
We still don't know the most important part.
I know.
Golem is in the hands of the Great Emperor.
They know too much.
We have to sacrifice a planet
in order to seize Earth anyway.
Destroy Zemuria.
Are you leading me into this, Teresa ?
What is it ?!
A planet-wide tectonic shift has started !
All hands, to your posts !
Prepare to launch the Yamato !
Why don't you attack already ?
Orders from Defense HQ to all fleets !
Hold out no matter what.
Maintain the defense line.
Holding for one day means
we can send reinforcements.
The size doubles in two days,
and it'll be even greater in three days.
As long as we have the Time Fault,
our war potential is unlimited.
Don't be scared. Fight.
For Earth, and for the future of our children.
We must not let our civilization,
or the human species go extinct.
Survive regardless of the cost,
no matter how bad things get.
A.I. operated autonomous control...
I'm the only crewman, huh ?
It's sad, don't you think so too, Andromeda ?
Three Medalusa-class ships destroyed !
We're just getting started !
Keep pushing  !
Rotate the catapult !
Launch the Desvatators !
A large number of spacecraft have
launched from a massive enemy carrier.
Prepare to fire rapid torpedoes and cluster missiles...
...followed by a barrage of graviton spread shots !
Fire !
Message from the Aldebaran.
We'll hold this place.
Break apart the shield and
withdraw to the other side of Mars.
No, for the honor of Garmillas, we can't...
Another fleet is coming, directly from Earth.
All ships, prepare to fire wave motion guns !
Fire !
Take off as the ground gives way.
Starting the auxiliary engines.
Now, Kodai !
Raise the hull !
High energy signature, incoming !
Launch the Yamato !
Get into communications range no matter
what, and inform Earth about Golem.
Engine, maximum output !
This is no longer a matter of Earth or Gatlantis.
As long as the Time Fault exists,
the killing will never end.
I thought I'd chosen the best
option to restore Earth, but...
If only I could destroy the gravitational core.
Why are they destroying their own planet ?
What ?
Say it again !
The losses of the Earth-Garmillas
joint forces have exceeded 50%
This ship will not return to combat.
HQ ordered us to proceed with Plan G.
I will partially assume command of this ship.
We're under an A.I.'s command ?
What's the meaning of this ?
What's Plan G ?
The Time Fault can produce weapons
endlessly, but humans have a limit.
The solutions are to reduce
personnel by using A.I.s...
...and raise weapon usage
efficiency by modifying human bodies.
We don't know what kind of choices
humans will have to make in order to survive.
That's why we preserve normal genes
while we can, and when the worst comes...
"...we leave Earth to look for a new home."
Is that Plan G ?
But how ?
Even if we have reproductive cells,
it's not easy to produce humans.
The ship is not equipped with such a lab...
Correct. That's why most of the
Ginga crew members are female.
Artificial reproduction will
eventually become real, but for now...
We're humanity's last line of defense.
Even if we mechanize
our limbs, the body is still...
In order for humans to survive...
Do we have to go that far ?!
In order to overcome fear,
you must become fear...
...such as the wave motion gun fleet and military expansion with the Time Fault.
It was mankind's decision after the
devastation of the war with Garmillas.
It's in order to live on in this cruel world,
since humans are too weak.
From Andromeda to all ships.
Do you copy ?
I found the Yamato !
It was very brief, but I was
able to visually detect it.
It was the Yamato !
The Yamato is alive !
Yamato...
But it's caught in the
Comet Empire's massive gravitational field.
It's impossible for the Yamato to break free.
Remaining ships, if you hear me,
help the Yamato escape.
This ship will approach the center of the Comet, and
attempt to destroy the gravitational core of the enemy.
That's suicide !
The Andromeda is by itself with no escort !
On top of that, the Andromeda alone can't hold out
against the gravitational core that controls so much mass.
Captain, I have an idea.
Ginga's Cosmo Reverse
can amplify wave motion guns.
The Andromeda alone should then be
able to damage the gravitational core.
The CRS will be over-stressed in
order to obtain the expected results.
We can't afford to lose the Cosmo Reverse System for an uncertain operation...
I didn't ask your opinion !
Captain.
So many lives have been lost.
I can't claim responsibility for it anymore, but...
...take the Andromeda and my life,
so you can come home, Yamato.
Yamanami...
No dead person can take responsibility, Yamanami.
Live...
...live and dust yourself off.
No matter how humiliating it is, survive.
Humans are weak, and make mistakes.
What's wrong with that ?
We are not...
...machines.
Plan G must be prioritized...
Machines don't feel shame.
...for the survival of mankind.
Humility and mistakes make humans special.
This ship must immediately...
Captain !
The Command A.I. is recalled as of now !
I'm assuming command of this ship !
Troubleshoot A-7, system rebooted !
Take the Ginga to the Mars combat zone !
Rapid torpedoes, fire !
You're a tough one, Andromeda.
Prepare to fire the wave motion gun !
Captain Yamanami, take me with you...
...so we both can survive.
Ginga
Cosmo Reverse, running at maximum capacity.
This shot will render it useless.
That's fine.
This is our ship, a human one.
Amplification rate 8 million TPa.
Activate the Cosmo Reverse !
Fire the wave motion gun !
I can't steer !
Three seconds till shock-wave passage !
Engine, maximum output !
Roger !
Zemuria has been destroyed !
Forced contact of rocket anchors !
We're being pulled !
That's the Andromeda.
All ships, leave the White Comet !
The Andromeda's heavily damaged !
It's critical !
Yamato...
You're alive...
You're really alive !
Black Birds, launch all spacecraft and
defend the Yamato and Andromeda.
Roger !
We're done for, huh ?
What the...?!
This is Kato of the Black Birds.
Do you copy ?
Reporting the successful
rescue of Captain Yamanami.
I repeat.
Captain Yamanami, successfully rescued.
Episode 21
Escape from Nightmare !!
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Sanada Shiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Niimi Kaoru:
Saijo Miki:
Kato Saburo:
Yamamoto Akira:
Katsuragi Touko:
Saito Hajime Saito:
Nagakura Shiori:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Otsuka Hochu
Mugihito
Hisakawa Aya
Moriya Satomi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Tanaka Rie
Kaida Yuko
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Hijikata Ryu:
Todo Saki:
Kanzaki Megumi
Ichinose Mina:
Kusakabe Urara:
A.I.
Yamanami Osamu:
Todo Heikuro:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Kusumi Naomi
Takagaki Ayahi
Hayashibara Megumi
Kurosawa Tomoyo
Komiya Arisa
Cho
Ebara Masashi
Kojima Toshihiko
Genda Tessho
Cottony clouds drift high across the sky
Sora takaku nagareru kieyuku wata no kumo
Klaus Keyman:
Loren Barrel:
Fomt Burger:
Zorder:
Gailane:
Balzey:
Todo Chiaki:
Tani Kozo:
Comm Officer:
Operator A:
Operator B:
Storyteller A:
Storyteller B:
Kamiya Hiroshi
Terasoma Masaki
Suwabe Junichi
Tezuka Hideaki
Shibata Hidekatsu
Nishimura Tomomichi
Sugiyama Kazuko
Ikeda Masaru
Fujinuma Kent
Yoshimura Kotaro
Yano Masaaki
Ikeshita Ririko
Matsumoto Yuki
Holding out both hands, I stretch out in the falling leaves
Ryoote wo age ah senobi shita rakuyou
As the house lights come on, I wish to meet people smiling at each other
Akari tomoru mado waraiau hito ni aitai to omou
Believing in a miraculous enounter to become real, I shout out for love
Sou kanau hazusa kiseki no deai ni ai sakenda
Luminous lives meet and bond with each other
Kagayaku jinsei no meguriawase tsumuideyuku
Let’s keep on living our lives
Bokura no jinsei wo tayumazu ni susumi tsuzukeyou
Let’s begin the story of our lives
Bokura no jinsei no monogatari wo saa hajimeyou
Preview
Can we talk to Zorder one more time ?
Tell me, how does one break
free from the puppeteer ?
There's only one way.
No enemy contact,
except for one, the Neues Deusula.
Keep going. Crash into it !
Episode 22
Destined Duel !